Rick Farouni | Curriculum Vitae

Department of Psychology, The Ohio State University nttp://rfarouni.github.io/

I am currently a doctoral candidate in quantitative psychology at the Ohio State University. I also hold a master's degree in mathematical statistics from OSU. I have excellent skills in scientific computing and a strong background in machine learning, multivariate statistics, and Bayesian statistics. My research is focused both on the statistical analysis of fMRI neuroimaging data and on nonparametric Bayesian modeling of longitudinal and time-series data in psychology.

Education

Academic Qualifications	
The Ohio State University PhD in Quantitative Psychology Advisor: Professor Robert Cudeck	Ohio, USA 2012-Present

The Ohio State University Ohio, USA Master of Science in Statistics 2012-2014

The Ohio State University Ohio, USA Master's Degree in Quantitative Psychology 2012-2014

Thesis Project: 'Latent Variable Modelling of Categorical Item Responses in a Hierarchical Bayesian Framework'

Bachelor's Degree in Psychology 2011-2012

Pennsylvania, USA

Seattle

Course Projects.....

- Multivariate Statistics (STAT 7560): 'Retinotopic Mapping of the Human Visual Cortex Using Independent Component Analysis'
- Advanced Computational Statistics (STAT 7730): 'Bayesian Analysis of Noisy Images Using Markov Random Fields'
- Statistical Consulting (STAT 6750): 'Modelling Categorical Perception of Speech Sounds using Beta Regression'

Conference Presentations

Joint Statistical Montings

The Pennsylvania State University

_	Source Statistical Meetings	Scattle
O	Poster Title: Across-Subject Predictive Modeling of fMRI BOLD Responses to Faces	2015
-	Awards and Fellowships	

Graduate Student Conference Presentation Award The Ohio State University 2015 The Center for Cognitive and Brain Sciences Summer Graduate Fellowship The Ohio State University 2015 **Project Proposal**: 'Decoding the Pixels of the Face Image from the Voxels of fMRI BOLD Activity Patterns' The Social and Behavioral Sciences Summer Fellowship The Ohio State University 2014 **University Fellowship**

The Ohio State University 2012

Experience

Teaching Experience.....

Graduate Teaching Associate Ohio, USA The Ohio State University 2013-present Teaching Assistant for Psychology 2220: Data Analysis in Psychology **Test Preparation Instructor** Moscow, Russia

Instructor of the Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT) 2009-2012

Teacher of English as a Foreign Language Moscow, Russia Teacher of General and Academic English 2001-2009

Journal Review Service.

Psychometrika Journal Peer Reviewer 2015 **Psychological Methods** Journal Peer Reviewer 2015

Computing and Language Skills

Programming and Software Skills.....

- o Programming Languages: Proficient in numerical and statistical computing languages. Comfortable working with and transitioning between Julia, R, Python, and Matlab depending on computing goals. Strong command of probabilistic programming languages such as Stan. Experienced in building deep learning models. Basic familiarity with statically typed programming languages such as Java.
- Computing Tools and Software: Experience with a variety of technologies such as LATEX, Linux OS, Git. Basic knowledge in website development tools such as HTML, CSS, and Jekyll.
- Supercomputing: Good knowledge of running numerical analyses on the Ohio Supercomputer Center's main clusters.

Languages • English, Arabic, Russian, Spanish (limited)